actual Logic Pro 12.2 capture
local MCP server / no cloud audio upload
Logic Pro MCP
safe first-look demo for a working Logic user
Real Logic Pro 12.2 screen capture. Not a DAW mockup.
The MCP server runs locally; core control does not require
uploading the project or audio.
I would not ask you to try this on a livelihood session first.
Start on a duplicate project or a disposable test session.
Use case 1: inspect before acting.
Read-only resources expose transport, tracks, mixer, project metadata,
MIDI ports, stock plugins, and workflow skills.
Before any risky write: fail-closed targets.
Track, mixer, plugin, MIDI import, marker, and project operations
require explicit targets and validation.
After a write: readback and provenance.
A command is not treated as success just because it was sent;
it must be observed or reported as uncertain or failed.
Good first high-trust task: exact stock plugin insertion.
Require an empty slot, insert only an allowlisted plugin,
read the slot back, and rollback on mismatch.
What I would show in a longer Loom:
duplicate project -> read state -> guarded action -> readback
-> cleanup or undo -> test evidence.
Not claiming production safety for every session yet.
The goal is to earn trust by proving what happened, not by hiding uncertainty.