actual Logic Pro 12.2 capture
local MCP server / no cloud audio upload
Logic Pro MCP: safety-first use-case demo
Built for the concern: "Logic is my livelihood; I cannot have it crash or fail."
MCP safety flow
Real DAW footage is shown on the left. The proof panel explains the safe operating sequence.
TITLE
For a working Logic user
You asked for a video. I agree:
a DAW tool needs visible evidence,
not trust-me claims.
This is a safety-first use-case cut,
not a promise to run on a live
client session today.
scene 1 / 8
START SAFELY
Duplicate/test project first
I would not point this at
a livelihood session as
the first test.
Good first target: a copied project,
an old session, or a disposable
Logic file.
Suggested first test:
- duplicate project
- disposable session
- no client deadline
scene 2 / 8
STEP 1
Read before acting
Read-only MCP resources expose
health, project info, transport,
tracks, mixer, MIDI ports,
stock plugins, and workflow skills.
First useful operation:
what is in this session,
and what looks risky?
Read-only resources:
logic://system/health
logic://project/info
logic://tracks
logic://mixer
scene 3 / 8
STEP 2
Plan before mutation
A useful assistant should produce
a cleanup/export/routing plan
before changing anything.
If the plan is vague,
the tool should stay in planning mode
instead of touching Logic.
Planning mode:
- inspect state
- list risks
- propose small steps
- ask before mutation
scene 4 / 8
STEP 3
Guarded action example
Example: insert a stock Gain plugin
into an exact empty slot.
The request must name the project path,
track, insert slot, plugin identity,
mode, and confirmation.
Guarded write shape:
project_expected_path
track + exact insert
allowlisted plugin
confirmed mode
scene 5 / 8
STEP 4
Readback or no success
The command is not considered
successful just because it was sent.
It must read the slot back,
confirm the expected plugin, or report
uncertainty/failure. Rollback on mismatch.
Honest result:
State A = confirmed
State B = uncertain
State C = failed
no fake success
scene 6 / 8
BOUNDARIES
What this is not claiming
Not production-safe for every
Logic version, locale, project shape,
or plugin window yet.
The point is to make the boundary
visible instead of hiding uncertainty
behind an AI demo.
Current trust scope:
- Logic Pro 12.2 evidence
- local host testing
- stock-plugin guardrails
- more Loom proof needed
scene 7 / 8
NEXT LOOM
The longer demo should show
duplicate project -> read state
-> guarded action -> readback
-> cleanup/undo -> test evidence
That is the bar: boring trust,
local operation, and proof of
what actually happened.
One clean proof run:
1. duplicate
2. read
3. act
4. verify
5. cleanup
scene 8 / 8